<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">
<concept id="it">
    <title>Italy</title>
    <shortdesc>Italian cuisine</shortdesc>
    <conbody>
        <p>Italian cuisine is food typical of Italy. It has developed through centuries of social and economic changes, with roots stretching to antiquity.
            Significant changes occurred with the discovery of the New World and the introduction of potatoes, tomatoes, capsicums, maize and sugar beet, 
            this last introduced in quantity in the 18th century.Italian cuisine is known for its regional diversity, 
            especially between the north and the south of the Italian peninsula.It offers an abundance of taste, and is one of the most popular and copied 
            in the world. It influenced several cuisines around the world, chiefly that of the United States.
            Italian cuisine is generally characterized by its simplicity, with many dishes having only two to four main ingredients.
            Italian cooks rely chiefly on the quality of the ingredients rather than on elaborate preparation.
            Ingredients and dishes vary by region. Many dishes that were once regional have proliferated with variations throughout the country.</p>
        
        <image conref="../tasks/Gnochi.dita#gnochi/gn"></image>
        
        <p><q>In Italy, Italian food is heavily seasonal," LaRaia says. "Any restaurant serving regional cuisine will be serving the protein that 
            you see on the side of the road. If you drive past chickens, expect to see chicken on the menu."</q>
         
         <image conref="../tasks/Spaghetti-alle-vongole.dita#Spavong/sp"></image>
         
            <q>"Everything is incredibly fresh and local and very simple," she says. "Even at the autogrills [Italian quick service restaurants, 
            often attached to gas stations] you're getting very fresh food, 
            it's very seasonal — you can get buffalo mozzarella and see the cows roaming in the back."</q></p>
    </conbody>
</concept>
